<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<eml:eml xmlns:eml="eml://ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.1.1" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="eml://ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.1.1 http://rs.gbif.org/schema/eml-gbif-profile/1.1/eml.xsd"
        packageId="10.15468/dl.7tthpt"  system="http://gbif.org" scope="system"
  xml:lang="en">

<dataset>
        <alternateIdentifier>0046460-191105090559680</alternateIdentifier>
    <title>GBIF Occurrence Download 10.15468/dl.7tthpt</title>
    <creator>
    <individualName>
          <surName>GBIF Download Service</surName>
    </individualName>
<electronicMailAddress>support@gbif.org</electronicMailAddress>    </creator>
    <metadataProvider>
    <individualName>
          <surName>GBIF Download Service</surName>
    </individualName>
<electronicMailAddress>support@gbif.org</electronicMailAddress>    </metadataProvider>
      <pubDate>
      2020-01-20
      </pubDate>
    <language>ENGLISH</language>
    <abstract>
        <para>A dataset containing all occurrences available in GBIF matching the query:
{
  &quot;TaxonKey&quot; : [ &quot;is Vitellaria paradoxa C.F.Gaertn.&quot; ]
}
The dataset includes records from the following constituent datasets. The full metadata for each constituent is also included in this archive:
1 records from Herbier Ecole de Faune
1 records from Field Museum of Natural History (Botany)  Seed Plant Collection
1 records from Djamde Wildlife Reserve in Togo: diversity of woody species
1 records from Data mobilized by the National Herbarium of Benin in the framework of the JRS Biodiversity project of Benin
1 records from Medicinal potential of African plants (Togo)
1 records from Botany (UPS)
1 records from Données d&apos;occurrence de l&apos;Herbier de l&apos;Université Jean Lorougnon Guédé
1 records from Université Pédagogique Nationale de Kinshasa (UPN). Plantes phytosanitaires. - Projet CABIN
1 records from Foretclasseemissahoe
1 records from Herbier National de Guinée (HNG)
1 records from Plants Of Nnamdi Azikiwe University Herbarium (NAUH) Awka
1 records from La liste (3) Rouge des plantes menacées de la Guinée
1 records from University of Graz, Institute of Plant Sciences - Herbarium GZU
1 records from Some Angiosperm Data of the Forest Herbarium Ibadan (FHI) Nigeria
1 records from Canadian Museum of Nature Palynology Collection
1 records from Inventaire des plantes alimentaires au Bénin
1 records from Université Pédagogique Nationale de Kinshasa (UPN). Plantes phytosanitaires. - Projet CABIN
1 records from Echantillon extrait des collections IBAAN
1 records from La seconde liste Rouge des plantes menacées de la Guinée (BID-AF2015-0042-NAC)
1 records from Inventory of Bonou, Kilibo and Lama forests (South and centre Benin)
1 records from Espèces végétales inventoriées dans les formations et strates de la forêt communautaire de Koussountou au Togo en 2017.
1 records from Inventory of plant species through Benin (West Africa)
1 records from Census in Agrimey forest reserve (southern Benin)
1 records from Espèces végétales inventoriées dans les formations et strates de la forêt classée de Missahoe au Togo en 2017.
1 records from The Vascular Plant Collection at the Botanische Staatssammlung München
1 records from Natural History Museum (London) Collection Specimens
2 records from CSIC-Real Jardín Botánico-Colección de Plantas Vasculares (MA)
2 records from Relevé floristique dans les bassins du fleuve Milo à Kankan	(CESP2016-022)
2 records from Biocultural Collection at the Natural History Museum of Denmark
2 records from Royal Museum of Central Africa - Metafro-Infosys - Xylarium
2 records from Collection of botanical drawings by Georg Schweinfurth at Herbarium Berolinense, Berlin (B)
3 records from NMNH Extant Specimen Records
3 records from Herbarium Berolinense, Berlin (B)
3 records from SysTax - Botanical Gardens
3 records from Occurrences des échantillons de plantes de l&apos;Herbier du Centre Suisse de Recherches Scientifiques (CSRS) en Côte d&apos;Ivoire
4 records from Moscow University Herbarium (MW)
4 records from International Barcode of Life project (iBOL)
4 records from Phanerogamic Botanical Collections (S)
5 records from The AAU Herbarium Database
5 records from Herbarium specimens of Université de Montpellier 2, Institut de Botanique (MPU))
5 records from Occurrences des échantillons de plantes de l&apos;Herbier de l&apos;Institut Botanique Aké-Assi d&apos;Andokoi (IBAAN), Côte d&apos;Ivoire
5 records from Additional list of gregarous Benin valuable species
5 records from Données d&apos;occurrences des spécimens des plantes menacées du Sénégal conservés à  l&apos;Herbier de l&apos;IFAN.
5 records from Tropicos Specimen Data
6 records from List of medicinal and agroforestry plants found in various ecosystems of Benin
6 records from Liste des récoltes par Herbier de dépôt TOGO
7 records from Royal Botanic Garden Edinburgh Herbarium (E)
7 records from Herbier CNRST/INERA
7 records from Census of the flora of Benin
8 records from Species composition in  twelve (12)  Afzelia africana  Sm &amp; Pers populations in Benin.
8 records from Plants of Ghana
8 records from Medicinal plants and associated plant collections at Ghana Herbarium
9 records from Census of fodder species through central and north of Benin
9 records from Togo National Herbarium Database
9 records from Forest edible fruits from Cameroon
9 records from Etude exploratoire des communautés végétales des forêts classées de Kilibo et Youi
9 records from herbarium_database
9 records from Herbier du Bénin
9 records from Liste des pays par taxon spécimen TOGO
10 records from Census of plant species in Monts-Kouffè regions, center Benin
10 records from Inventaire floristique dans le cadre le cadre de l&apos;Aménagement de la forêt classé de l&apos;Amou-Mono (Togo)
11 records from Inventory of plant species in the municipal forests of Nonsinasson, Gbede, Pele, Toukou, Fita, Wogbo, Bobe (Benin, West Africa)
12 records from Royal Botanic Gardens, Kew - Herbarium Specimens
12 records from Distribution de quelques espèces végétales du Bénin
12 records from Les Rubiaceae, Orchidaceae, Moraceae, Sapindaceae, Malvaceae, Melastomataceae, Verbenaceae, Loganiaceae, Sapotaceae, Scrophulariaceae, Sterculiaceae, Liliaceae, Meliaceae, Ochnaceae, Tiliaceae, Rosaceae, Solanaceae, Violaceae, Zingiberaceae, Myrtaceae, Rutaceae, Loranthaceae et quelques 71 autres familles de plantes de l&apos;Herbier du Centre National de Floristique en Côte d&apos;Ivoire.
14 records from Census of medicinal plants of Benin.
14 records from Carnet en Ligne
14 records from Plan Aménagement et de Gestion Simplifié (PAGS) des forèts sacrées des départements de l&apos;Ouémé-Plateau et le Collines. Données mobilisées dans le cadre du projet JRS Bénin
15 records from Bassins versants de vere et nalon (BID-AF2015-0066-REG)
16 records from Liste de quelques espèces à statuts particuliers de l&apos;herbier du Centre National de Floristique (CNF) en Côte d&apos;Ivoire
19 records from Herbarium Senckenbergianum (FR)
19 records from Distribution de quelques espèces de plantes et de Mimusops andongensis au Bénin
20 records from Biodiversité végétale de quelques écosystèmes au Bénin
22 records from Inventory of Penessoulou forest (North West Benin)
28 records from Census of the threatened species of Benin.
28 records from Geographically tagged INSDC sequences
30 records from Inventory of Dogo-Kétou forest (South-Benin). Data mobilized in the framework of JRS Biodiversity Foundation project
33 records from Gregarous Benin valuable species
35 records from Diversité et distribution de quelques espèces de plantes agroforestières au Bénin
39 records from Inventory of Bassila forest (North-Benin)
39 records from Forest inventory for above ground carbon estimation in  Biosphere Reserve of W.
40 records from Census of the species of Benin. Data mobilized in the framework of JRS Benin project and funded by JRS Biodiversity Foundation
41 records from Meise Botanic Garden Herbarium (BR)
42 records from Floral inventory of the natural pastures of the municipalities bordering the W Transboundary Biosphere Reserve in the Alibori department and the municipalities of Dassa_Zoume and Glazoué in the Collines department (Benin).
43 records from iNaturalist Research-grade Observations
46 records from Royal Botanic Gardens, Kew - Economic Botany Collection Specimens
50 records from Diversité des plantes des parcours naturels et des forêts  au Bénin
52 records from Ecological inventory of Borassus aethiopum (Mart.) populations in the Pendjari Biosphere Reserve, Benin. Data mobilized in the framework of JRS Benin project
55 records from Inventory of Wari maro forest (Benin)
56 records from Census of species recorded during phytosociological surveys in Benin
67 records from Data on agroforestry plant species of Benin
69 records from Plant inventory of W Biosphere reserve (North-Benin). Data mobilized in the framework of JRS Biodiversity Foundation project
70 records from Plan d&apos;Aménagement participative de la Forêt Classée d&apos;Alédjo (Togo)
77 records from A global database for the distributions of crop wild relatives
80 records from Naturalis Biodiversity Center (NL) - Botany
81 records from Census of medicinal and agroforestry plants of Benin
82 records from Elaboration de table de tarif de cubage multispécifique (I)
101 records from Agroforestry plant species found in protected areas and riparian lands in Sudano-guinean and Sudanian agroecological zones. Data mobilized in the framework of BID National project BID-AF2015-0065-NAC and funded by EU
107 records from African Plants - a photo guide
117 records from Agroforestry species in Parkia biglobosa&apos;s parklands in Northern Benin
123 records from Distribution de quelques espèces de plantes agroforestières et médicinales au Bénin
125 records from Study of medicinal and energy plants from Benin
137 records from Census of plant species of Benin (West Africa): Database4
198 records from The vascular plants collection (P) at the Herbarium of the Muséum national d&apos;Histoire Naturelle (MNHN - Paris)
215 records from Census of agroforestry plant species of Benin (West Africa) by SOS Biodiversity
359 records from West African Vegetation Database
1025 records from Elaboration du tarif de cubage multispécifique
1740 records from FLOTROP, a massive contribution to plant diversity data for open ecosystems in Tropical Africa.
2020 records from Diversité des espèces menacées des zones classées et terroirs villageois du Bénin (Afrique de l&apos;Ouest).
2868 records from Diversité floristique des espèces menacées prioritaires du Bénin (Afrique de l&apos;Ouest).
5083 records from The census of national forest of  Benin .
</para>
    </abstract>
      <contact>
    <individualName>
          <surName>GBIF Download Service</surName>
    </individualName>
<electronicMailAddress>support@gbif.org</electronicMailAddress>      </contact>

</dataset>

<additionalMetadata>
    <metadata>
      <gbif>
        <dateStamp>2020-01-20T15:36:10Z</dateStamp>
      <citation identifier="10.15468/dl.7tthpt">GBIF Occurrence Download 10.15468/dl.7tthpt</citation>
              <physical>
                  <objectName>Darwin Core Archive</objectName>
                  <characterEncoding>UTF-8</characterEncoding>
                  <dataFormat>
                      <externallyDefinedFormat>
                          <formatName>Darwin Core Archive</formatName>
                      </externallyDefinedFormat>
                  </dataFormat>
                  <distribution>
                      <online>
                          <url function="download">http://api.gbif.org/v1/occurrence/download/request/0046460-191105090559680.zip</url>
                      </online>
                  </distribution>
              </physical>
        </gbif>
    </metadata>
</additionalMetadata>

</eml:eml>
