<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<eml:eml xmlns:eml="eml://ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.1.1" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="eml://ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.1.1 http://rs.gbif.org/schema/eml-gbif-profile/1.1/eml.xsd"
        packageId="441c8c19-d61b-4d2b-aa90-26031d337366"  system="http://gbif.org" scope="system"
  xml:lang="en">

<dataset>
      <alternateIdentifier>10.15468/g8pbz5</alternateIdentifier>
        <alternateIdentifier>http://ipt-benin.gbif.fr/resource?r=toko</alternateIdentifier>
    <title>Diversité des espèces menacées des zones classées et terroirs villageois du Bénin (Afrique de l&apos;Ouest).</title>
    <creator>
    <individualName>
<givenName>Ismaïla</givenName>          <surName>TOKO IMOROU</surName>
    </individualName>
<organizationName>University of Abomey-Calavi</organizationName><positionName>Professor</positionName>    <address>
<city>Calavi</city><administrativeArea>Atlantique</administrativeArea><postalCode>229</postalCode><country>BENIN</country>    </address>
<electronicMailAddress>ismael_toko@yahoo.fr</electronicMailAddress><onlineUrl>http://0022997772872</onlineUrl>    </creator>
    <metadataProvider>
    <individualName>
<givenName>Erick</givenName>          <surName>SOGBOSSI</surName>
    </individualName>
<organizationName>University of Abomey-Calavi</organizationName><positionName>Research Assistant</positionName>    <address>
<city>Calavi</city><administrativeArea>Atlantique</administrativeArea><postalCode>229</postalCode><country>BENIN</country>    </address>
<phone>0022996114887</phone><electronicMailAddress>ericksogbossi@gmail.com</electronicMailAddress>    </metadataProvider>
    <metadataProvider>
    <individualName>
<givenName>Sakibou</givenName>          <surName>BIAOU</surName>
    </individualName>
<organizationName>University of Abomey-Calavi</organizationName><positionName>Research assistant</positionName>    <address>
<city>Calavi</city><administrativeArea>Atlantique</administrativeArea><postalCode>229</postalCode><country>BENIN</country>    </address>
<electronicMailAddress>biakib@yahoo.fr</electronicMailAddress><onlineUrl>http://0022997435832</onlineUrl>    </metadataProvider>
    <associatedParty>
    <individualName>
<givenName>Jean</givenName>          <surName>Ganglo</surName>
    </individualName>
<electronicMailAddress>ganglocj@gmail.com</electronicMailAddress>    <role>USER</role>
    </associatedParty>
      <pubDate>
      2017-07-28
      </pubDate>
    <language>ENGLISH</language>
    <abstract>
        <para>Les données d&amp;#39;occurrence ont été encodées à partir des données de relevés phytosociologiques issus des travaux de recherche de maîtrise et de thèse de doctorat dans le Département de Géographie à l&amp;#39;Université d&amp;#39;Abomey-Calavi.</para>
    </abstract>
        <keywordSet>
              <keyword>Tchaourou</keyword>
              <keyword>Savè</keyword>
              <keyword>Cobly</keyword>
              <keyword>Malanville</keyword>
              <keyword>Natitingou</keyword>
              <keyword>Gogounou</keyword>
              <keyword>Zangnanado</keyword>
              <keyword>Kandi</keyword>
              <keyword>Bassila</keyword>
              <keyword>Occurrence? Bopa</keyword>
              <keyword>Dangbo</keyword>
              <keyword>Ouidah</keyword>
              <keyword>Wari-Maro</keyword>
              <keyword>Banikoara</keyword>
              <keywordThesaurus>GBIF Dataset Type Vocabulary: http://rs.gbif.org/vocabulary/gbif/dataset_type.xml</keywordThesaurus>
        </keywordSet>
      <intellectualRights>
        <para>This work is licensed under a <ulink url="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/legalcode"><citetitle>Creative Commons Attribution (CC-BY) 4.0 License</citetitle></ulink>.</para>
      </intellectualRights>
      <coverage>
            <geographicCoverage>
                  <geographicDescription>Les données d&apos;occurrence ont été encodées à partir des données de relevé phytosociologique issues des travaux de recherche de maîtrise et de thèse de doctorat dans le Dpépartement de Géographie à l&apos;Université d&apos;Abomey-Calavi.</geographicDescription>
                  <boundingCoordinates>
                      <westBoundingCoordinate>0.92</westBoundingCoordinate>
                      <eastBoundingCoordinate>3.76</eastBoundingCoordinate>
                      <northBoundingCoordinate>11.72</northBoundingCoordinate>
                      <southBoundingCoordinate>6.31</southBoundingCoordinate>
                  </boundingCoordinates>
            </geographicCoverage>
          <temporalCoverage>
            <rangeOfDates>
              <beginDate>
                <calendarDate>      2005-04-29
</calendarDate>
              </beginDate>
              <endDate>
                <calendarDate>      2016-12-07
</calendarDate>
              </endDate>
            </rangeOfDates>
          </temporalCoverage>
              <taxonomicCoverage>
                    <taxonomicClassification>
                          <taxonRankName>Kingdom</taxonRankName>
                        <taxonRankValue>Plantae</taxonRankValue>
                          <commonName>Plants</commonName>
                    </taxonomicClassification>
              </taxonomicCoverage>
      </coverage>
      <maintenance>
          <description>
              <para></para>
          </description>
          <maintenanceUpdateFrequency>unkown</maintenanceUpdateFrequency>
      </maintenance>
      <contact>
    <individualName>
<givenName>Ismaïla</givenName>          <surName>TOKO IMOROU</surName>
    </individualName>
<organizationName>University of Abomey-Calavi</organizationName><positionName>Professor</positionName>    <address>
<city>Calavi</city><administrativeArea>Atlantique</administrativeArea><postalCode>229</postalCode><country>BENIN</country>    </address>
<electronicMailAddress>ismael_toko@yahoo.fr</electronicMailAddress><onlineUrl>http://0022997772872</onlineUrl>      </contact>

      <project id="BID-AF2015-0066-REG">
          <title>Capacity building and biodiversity data mobilization for conservation, sustainable use, and decision making in Africa and Madagascar</title>
          <personnel>
    <individualName>
<givenName>Jean</givenName>          <surName>GANGLO</surName>
    </individualName>
    <role>PRINCIPAL_INVESTIGATOR</role>
          </personnel>
          <abstract>
              <para>This project to mobilize biodiversity data and identify conservation priorities will be implemented by a consortium of eight African countries – Senegal, Côte-d’Ivoire, Mali, Guinea, DRC, Niger, Madagascar, and Benin.
Training workshops organized by the University of Kansas will help build the data publishing capacity of project partners. The consortium will identify priority invasive alien species and threatened species for data mobilization, and publish relevant data from collections in France, Netherlands and Belgium. More than 200,000 records of biodiversity data will be made available through GBIF.org and national portals.
Based on published data, the consortium will develop distribution maps of priority species, suggest actions to monitor and control the spread of invasive alien species and provide recommendations for the conservation of threatened species.</para>
          </abstract>
          <funding>
              <para>The funding of this project is generously provided by European Union in the framework of Biodiversity Information for Development program managed by GBIF Secretariat</para>
          </funding>
            <studyAreaDescription>
                <descriptor name="generic" citableClassificationSystem="false">
                    <descriptorValue>The data digitized and published in the framework of this project are gathered throughout the country members on the targeted species</descriptorValue>
                </descriptor>
            </studyAreaDescription>
            <designDescription>
                <description>
                    <para>Despite its utmost importance to the survival of humanity, biodiversity is subject to many threats. As a significant step toward overcoming these threats, we submit this project in the framework of a consortium of eight African countries - Senegal, Côte-d’Ivoire, Mali, Guinea, DRC, Niger, Madagascar, and Benin - to achieve the following goals: 
1) Establish and strengthen international collaborations to mobilize biodiversity data; to achieve that goal, we will identify priority invasive alien species and threatened species to be considered in the consortium. We will organize workshops at regional level under the umbrella of the University of Kansas (USA), our Non-ACP partner, to capacitate project partners. We will digitize and publish data of consortium countries deposited in France, Netherlands, and Belgium. 
2) Increase available biodiversity data, within and beyond the grant period, by capacitating and providing financial assistance to in-country partners to encourage them mobilize and publish their data through GBIF and national portals. 
3) Apply biodiversity data in response to conservation priorities by achieving the following: elaborate distribution maps of threatened species and invasive alien species; identify the main threats to species and suggest efficient actions to protect and conserve them; identify and suggest efficient actions to monitor and eradicate invasive alien species; evaluate the efficiency of protected areas with respect to biodiversity conservation and make adequate suggestions; finally, from our results, elaborate and broadcast communication and outreach via diverse media so as to demonstrate to policy- and decision-makers the value chain: data → knowledge → applications.</para>
                </description>
            </designDescription>
      </project>
</dataset>

<additionalMetadata>
    <metadata>
      <gbif>
        <dateStamp>2020-01-20T15:36:10Z</dateStamp>
      <citation>TOKO IMOROU I, SOGBOSSI E, BIAOU S (2017). Diversité des espèces menacées des zones classées et terroirs villageois du Bénin (Afrique de l&apos;Ouest).. Laboratory of Forest Sciences (University of Abomey-Calavi). Occurrence dataset https://doi.org/10.15468/g8pbz5 accessed via GBIF.org on 2020-01-20.</citation>
              <bibliography>
      <citation>Kouta S., 2016. Impact de la mise en œuvre du plan d’aménagement de la forêt classée des Monts Kouffé sur la dynamique des formations végétales en République du Bénin. Diplôme d’Etudes Approfondies (DEA), DGAT/FLASH/UAC, 96 p.						
Biaou S., 2015. Cartographie des Changements de l’occupation des terres dans la forêt classée de Bassila (Afrique de l’Ouest). Mémoire de maîtrise en géographie, DGAT/FLASH/UAC, 115 p.						
Mazou I., 2014. Dynamique phytogéographique du district Borgou-Nord dans les arrondissements de Godounou et de Zougou-Pantrossi (Commune de Gogounou). Mémoire de maîtrise en géographie, DGAT/FLASH/UAC, 125 p.						
Mensah G. K. S., 2014. Gestion des terroirs et conservation de la biodiversité végétale dans les arrondissements de Koudo et de Houin (Commune de Lokossa). Mémoire de maîtrise en géographie, DGAT/FLASH/UAC, 112 p.						
Issifou Moumouni Y., 2014. Dynamique phytogéographique de la région soudanienne au Bénin : secteur du district Borgou-Nord (Arrondissements de Bagou Commune de Gogounou). Mémoire de maîtrise en géographie, DGAT/FLASH/UAC, 119 p.						
Moussa A. D., 2014. Cartographie des changements spatio-temporels de l’occupation du sol dans la forêt classée de Ballefoungou (commune de Djougou). Mémoire de maîtrise en géographie, DGAT/FLASH/UAC, 82 p.						
Djibril H., 2014. Construction des retenues d’hydrauliques pastorales et dynamique des formations végétales riveraines dans la commune de Kalalé au Bénin. Diplôme d’étude Approfondie (DEA), DGAT/FLASH/UAC, 130 p.						
Karimou S., 2013. Dynamique phytogéographique de la marge septentrionale de la zone soudano-guinéenne dans la Commune de Bembèrèkè : secteur centre (Arrondissement d&apos;Ina). Mémoire de maîtrise en géographie, DGAT/FLAH/UAC, 122 p.						
AROUNA O., 2012. Cartographie et modélisation prédictive des changements spatio-temporels de la végétation dans la Commune de Djidja au Bénin : implications pour l’aménagement du territoire. Thèse de Doctorat, FLASH/UAC, 246 p.						
Toko I. I., 2008. Etude de la variabilité spatiale de la biomasse herbacée, de la phénologie et de la structure de la végétation le long des topos séquences du bassin supérieur du fleuve Ouémé au Bénin. Thèse de Doctorat, FLASH/UAC, 241 p.</citation>
              </bibliography>
        </gbif>
    </metadata>
</additionalMetadata>

</eml:eml>
