<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<eml:eml xmlns:eml="eml://ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.1.1" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="eml://ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.1.1 http://rs.gbif.org/schema/eml-gbif-profile/1.1/eml.xsd"
        packageId="60954cb1-3b60-48e7-a2c1-75ffcb6d16cd"  system="http://gbif.org" scope="system"
  xml:lang="en">

<dataset>
      <alternateIdentifier>10.15468/3zjlhv</alternateIdentifier>
        <alternateIdentifier>http://ipt.gbifbenin.org/resource?r=occ_sunday</alternateIdentifier>
    <title>Census of plant species of Benin (West Africa): Database4</title>
    <creator>
    <individualName>
<givenName>Sunday</givenName>          <surName>KAKPO</surName>
    </individualName>
<organizationName>SOS Biodiversity</organizationName><positionName>Head</positionName>    <address>
<deliveryPoint>04bp1005</deliveryPoint><city>Cotonou</city><administrativeArea>Littoral</administrativeArea><postalCode>+229</postalCode><country>BENIN</country>    </address>
<phone>97123391</phone><electronicMailAddress>kakposunday@yahoo.fr</electronicMailAddress>    </creator>
    <metadataProvider>
    <individualName>
<givenName>Sunday</givenName>          <surName>KAKPO</surName>
    </individualName>
<organizationName>SOS Biodiversity</organizationName><positionName>Head</positionName>    <address>
<deliveryPoint>04bp1005</deliveryPoint><city>Cotonou</city><administrativeArea>Littoral</administrativeArea><postalCode>+229</postalCode><country>BENIN</country>    </address>
<phone>97123391</phone><electronicMailAddress>kakposunday@yahoo.fr</electronicMailAddress>    </metadataProvider>
    <metadataProvider>
    <individualName>
<givenName>Kourouma</givenName>          <surName>KOURA</surName>
    </individualName>
<organizationName>Laboratory of Forestry Sciences</organizationName><positionName>Assistant</positionName>    <address>
<deliveryPoint>04 BP 0004</deliveryPoint><city>Cotonou</city><administrativeArea>Littoral</administrativeArea><postalCode>+229</postalCode><country>BENIN</country>    </address>
<phone>96716130</phone><electronicMailAddress>kourakourouma@gmail.com</electronicMailAddress>    </metadataProvider>
    <metadataProvider>
    <individualName>
<givenName>Jean Cossi</givenName>          <surName>GANGLO</surName>
    </individualName>
<organizationName>Laboratory of Forestry Sciences</organizationName><positionName>Head</positionName>    <address>
<deliveryPoint>BP 1493</deliveryPoint><city>Abomey-Calavi</city><administrativeArea>Atlantique</administrativeArea><postalCode>+229</postalCode><country>BENIN</country>    </address>
<phone>66363770</phone><electronicMailAddress>ganglocj@gmail.com</electronicMailAddress>    </metadataProvider>
    <associatedParty>
    <individualName>
<givenName>Sunday</givenName>          <surName>B Kakpo</surName>
    </individualName>
<electronicMailAddress>kakposunday@yahoo.fr</electronicMailAddress>    <role>USER</role>
    </associatedParty>
      <pubDate>
      2019-05-06
      </pubDate>
    <language>ENGLISH</language>
    <abstract>
        <para>List of plant species recorded during studies for Obtaining of under degree,  Master degree and Engeneer degree in Agronomics Sciences</para>
    </abstract>
        <keywordSet>
              <keyword>Benin</keyword>
              <keyword>forest</keyword>
              <keyword>protected area</keyword>
              <keyword>West Africa</keyword>
              <keyword>Occurrence</keyword>
              <keywordThesaurus>GBIF Dataset Type Vocabulary: http://rs.gbif.org/vocabulary/gbif/dataset_type.xml</keywordThesaurus>
        </keywordSet>
      <intellectualRights>
        <para>This work is licensed under a <ulink url="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/legalcode"><citetitle>Creative Commons Attribution (CC-BY) 4.0 License</citetitle></ulink>.</para>
      </intellectualRights>
      <coverage>
            <geographicCoverage>
                  <geographicDescription>Benin (West Africa)</geographicDescription>
                  <boundingCoordinates>
                      <westBoundingCoordinate>0.982</westBoundingCoordinate>
                      <eastBoundingCoordinate>3.383</eastBoundingCoordinate>
                      <northBoundingCoordinate>10.066</northBoundingCoordinate>
                      <southBoundingCoordinate>9.784</southBoundingCoordinate>
                  </boundingCoordinates>
            </geographicCoverage>
          <temporalCoverage>
            <rangeOfDates>
              <beginDate>
                <calendarDate>      1998-07-01
</calendarDate>
              </beginDate>
              <endDate>
                <calendarDate>      2017-08-22
</calendarDate>
              </endDate>
            </rangeOfDates>
          </temporalCoverage>
              <taxonomicCoverage>
                    <generalTaxonomicCoverage>Plantae</generalTaxonomicCoverage>
                    <taxonomicClassification>
                          <taxonRankName>Kingdom</taxonRankName>
                        <taxonRankValue>Plantae</taxonRankValue>
                    </taxonomicClassification>
              </taxonomicCoverage>
      </coverage>
      <maintenance>
          <description>
              <para></para>
          </description>
          <maintenanceUpdateFrequency>unkown</maintenanceUpdateFrequency>
      </maintenance>
      <contact>
    <individualName>
<givenName>Sunday</givenName>          <surName>KAKPO</surName>
    </individualName>
<organizationName>SOS Biodiversity</organizationName><positionName>Head</positionName>    <address>
<deliveryPoint>04bp1005</deliveryPoint><city>Cotonou</city><administrativeArea>Littoral</administrativeArea><postalCode>+229</postalCode><country>BENIN</country>    </address>
<phone>97123391</phone><electronicMailAddress>kakposunday@yahoo.fr</electronicMailAddress>      </contact>

      <project id="http://jrsbiodiversity.org/jrs-supports-capacity-development-uac-oxford-2018/ ; http://jrsbiodiversity.org/grants/uac-2018/">
          <title>Regional graduate course for capacity development in biodiversity informatics in Africa</title>
          <personnel>
    <individualName>
<givenName>Jean Cossi</givenName>          <surName>GANGLO</surName>
    </individualName>
    <role>POINT_OF_CONTACT</role>
          </personnel>
          <abstract>
              <para>Through key objectives, this project is designed to overcome the challenge of lack of capacities in Africa: 
Objective 1: Build in-depth capacities in biodiversity informatics to students in masters program:
At least 20 Beninese students and 10 students of other nationalities will be yearly recruited and fully capacitated in the program (Months 4, 16, 28 and beyond the project) (Output 1). The courses will be recorded and shared worldwide (Outcome 4).
Objective 2: Build capacities in biodiversity informatics to other GBIF Benin partners (students and professionals):
Through workshops, at least, each year, 50 other GBIF Benin partners will be trained in relevant topics of biodiversity informatics (Months 6, 12, 18, 24, 30, 34 and beyond) (Output 5)
Objective 3: Fill data gaps in priority thematic areas of Benin and other countries involved in the project:
Trained students will achieve data gaps analysis in priority thematic areas (Months 12 – 36 and beyond) (Output 6) and contribute to fill data gaps (Months 12 – 36 and beyond) (Output 7). 
Objective 4: Use data to develop appropriate products to inform decisions on biodiversity conservation:
Trained students will use data to address needs of information (Months 12 – 36 and beyond) (Output 8) and largely disseminate the results via multimedia (Months 12 – 36 and beyond) (Output 9).
Project Objective 5: Enhance staff development:
We will provide internship opportunities to strengthen capacities of national trainers and most brilliant students to enable them to sustainably carry on the training of students in the program</para>
          </abstract>
          <funding>
              <para>The funding of this project is generously provided by JRS Biodiversity Foundation (http://jrsbiodiversity.org/)</para>
          </funding>
            <studyAreaDescription>
                <descriptor name="generic" citableClassificationSystem="false">
                    <descriptorValue>Actually in Benin, we estimate that there are 400 – 600 working biodiversity information scientists in public and private agencies. With few exceptions, the situation is not much different in the rest of African countries. Those biodiversity information scientists usually base their decisions - of biodiversity conservation - on floristic and faunistic compositions of ecosystems and related communities as well as on ecology, ethology and habitat characteristics of different species. This approach becomes limiting to conserve efficiently and sustainably biodiversity in the actual threatening context of climate and global changes exacerbated by diverse pressures on biodiversity. To overcome that limitation, we rather need a critical mass of scientists with sound knowledge in biodiversity informatics to achieve relevant results on spatial distributions, ecological niches… of species and different biota to inform decisions on priority areas of biodiversity.
 In order to develop a trained cohort to meet national needs, we believe that Benin needs to train at least an additional 20 master students. Additionally, training each year at least 10 other masters and advanced students from different African countries, will result in progressive but efficient creation of homes of biodiversity informatics to enhance biodiversity conservation and sustainable uses throughout Africa.</descriptorValue>
                </descriptor>
            </studyAreaDescription>
            <designDescription>
                <description>
                    <para>The work plan of the project is presented per objective:
Objective 1: Build in-depth capacities in biodiversity informatics to students in masters program
We will recruit students every year (Activity 1) at least 20 Beninese students and 10 students of other nationalities (Months 4, 16, 28 and beyond) (Output 1).Students will be fully trained in relevant topics of biodiversity informatics by national and international experts (Months 1-36 and beyond) (Activity 2) so that, after two years of training, at least 80% of students successfully graduate (Months 18, 30 and beyond) (Output 2). The courses will be recorded and shared (Months 1-36) (Activity 3) to enable worldwide use and reuse (Outcome 3).
Objective 2: Build capacities in biodiversity informatics to other GBIF Benin partners (students and professionals)
Here, we will enhance, through one Professional Skills Workshop per year, capacity buildings to other GBIF Benin partners (Months 6, 18, 30and beyond) (Activity 4) by training yearly, at least 50 of them in relevant topics of biodiversity informatics (Output 4). Therefore, data gap analysis, data collection, and data uses will be promoted (Outcome 4). 
Objective 3: Whenever deemed relevant, identify and fill data gaps in priority thematic areas of Benin and other countries involved in the project
Whenever relevant, trained students will achieve data gaps analysis (Months 12 – 36 and beyond) (Activity 5) in at least 3 priority thematic areas of their respective countries (Months 12 – 36 and beyond) (Output 5); they will then collect and publish data (Months 12 – 36 and beyond) (Activity 6) to fill the gaps identified (Months 12 – 36 and beyond) (Output 5). Therefore, data gap analysis, data collection, and data uses will be promoted (Outcome 4). 
Objective 4: Use data to develop appropriate products to inform decisions on biodiversity conservation
To attain that objective, trained students will use data (Months 12 – 36 and beyond) (Activity 7) to address needs of information (species, biota spatial distributions and niche models…) to support biodiversity conservation (Months 12 – 36 and beyond) (Output 7). We will then, through Communication and Outreach Workshops (1 per year), achieve communication and outreach (Months 12 – 36 and beyond) (Activity 8) to largely disseminate the products developed, in government agencies, NGOs, universities, private sectors… (Months 12 – 36 and beyond) (Output 8). Therefore, detailed and data products developed will be promoted in decision making (Outcome 5).
Objective 5: Enhance staff development
Here, we will provide internship opportunities to national trainers and most brilliant students to strengthen their capacities so that they can reliably carry on the training of students (Months 1 – 36 and beyond) (Activity 9) to sustain in the program (Outcome 7)</para>
                </description>
            </designDescription>
      </project>
</dataset>

<additionalMetadata>
    <metadata>
      <gbif>
        <dateStamp>2020-01-20T15:36:09Z</dateStamp>
      <citation>KAKPO S, KOURA K, GANGLO J C (2019). Census of plant species of Benin (West Africa): Database4. SOS Biodiversity. Occurrence dataset https://doi.org/10.15468/3zjlhv accessed via GBIF.org on 2020-01-20.</citation>
              <bibliography>
      <citation>AKUEDOKPO Sêna Clémence, 2015. Etude diagnostique du jardin botanique de Bohicon et analyse ethnobotanique des plantes antidiabétiques et anti hypertensives. Licence Professionnelle, Faculté des Sciences Agronomiques, Université d’Abomey-Calavi, Bénin.						
Alain Kpèdékpo GBEFFE, 2011. Ecologie, phytosociologie et contributions diverses de Andropogon gayanus, Brachiaria jubata, Loxodera ledermanii, Tephrosia pedicellata, et Alysicarpus ovalifolius dans la réserve de biosphère transfrontalière du W (BENIN). Diplôme d’Ingénieur Agronome, Faculté des Sciences Agronomiques, Université d’Abomey-Calavi, Bénin.						
AZONTONDE Urielle Claudia, 2013. Etude diagnostique de la Direction du Parc National du W (DPNW) et mode de gestion des fruitiers sauvages au sein des terroirs riverains. Licence Professionnelle, Faculté des Sciences Agronomiques, Université d’Abomey-Calavi, Bénin.						
Cadine ALLADASSI, 2011. Fonctionnement et gestion des écosystèmes naturels : Productivité et Capacité de charge des pâturages naturels de la Réserve de Biosphère Transfrontalière du W (BENIN). Diplôme d’Ingénieur Agronome, Faculté des Sciences Agronomiques, Université d’Abomey-Calavi, Bénin.						
Charbel Vivien Gérardy TOHINNOU HOUEZE, 2015. Etude diagnostique du secteur forestier de Massi : recensement et importance des espèces appartenant à la famille des rubiaceae dans la lama. Licence Professionnelle, Faculté des Sciences Agronomiques, Université d’Abomey-Calavi, Bénin.						
Clarel. Y. AMETEPE, 2015. Diagnostic de l’Inspection Forestière Mono-Couffo : Recensement des plantes antihypertensives et antidiabétiques et contribution à l’aménagement de la forêt sacrée (Houin). Licence Professionnelle, Faculté des Sciences Agronomiques, Université d’Abomey-Calavi, Bénin.						
Coffi Firmin FANOU, 2013. Etude diagnostique de la direction du parc national de pendjari et problématique de gestion des plantes utilisées dans le traitement de diabète dans les terroirs riverains. Licence Professionnelle, Faculté des Sciences Agronomiques, Université d’Abomey-Calavi, Bénin.						
Curie Prosny Sènami HOUEHOUME GANSE, 2016. Perceptions locales de la dégradation du couvert forestier et son impact sur les ressources en eau dans la partie méridionale du bassin versant du zou. Diplôme de Master Professionnel, Faculté des Sciences Agronomiques, Université d’Abomey-Calavi, Bénin.						
DAÏ Emilienne Houévo, 2013.  Etude diagnostique de la direction du parc national de la pendjari et problématique de gestion des plantes aromatiques, des épices et des colorants dans les terroirs riverains. Licence Professionnelle, Faculté des Sciences Agronomiques, Université d’Abomey-Calavi, Bénin.						
Emilia Vanessa P. AGBO, 2015. Etude diagnostique du cantonnement forestier d’Abomey : recensement des plantes utilisées dans le traitement des maladies mentales. Licence Professionnelle, Faculté des Sciences Agronomiques, Université d’Abomey-Calavi, Bénin.						
Gbèssito Romaine ASSOGBA BALLE , 2016. Impacts Agro – Sanitaires et Floristiques de l’aménagement et de l’exploitation des bas-fonds dans la commune de Glazoué. Diplôme de Master Professionnel, Faculté des Sciences Agronomiques, Université d’Abomey-Calavi, Bénin.						
GLITO S. Mathias Renaud, 2006. Distribution géographique des ressources fourragères disponibles pour nourrir l’aulacode d’élevage au Bénin. Diplôme d’Ingénieur Agronome, Faculté des Sciences Agronomiques, Université d’Abomey-Calavi, Bénin. Diplôme d’Ingénieur Agronome, Faculté des Sciences Agronomiques, Université d’Abomey-Calavi, Bénin.						
GUEDOU Sènan Aimé, 2011. Identification et évaluation de la biomasse des ligneux fourragers accessibles aux bovins sur les parcours communautaires du nord-est Bénin. Diplôme d’Ingénieur Agronome, Faculté des Sciences Agronomiques, Université d’Abomey-Calavi, Bénin.						
Guillaume HOUNSOU-DINDIN, 2013. Etude diagnostique de la direction du parc national du w (dpnw) et problématique de gestion des plantes aromatiques épices et colorants dans les terroirs riverains. Licence Professionnelle, Faculté des Sciences Agronomiques, Université d’Abomey-Calavi, Bénin.						
Hospice Samson SOSSOU, 2013. Etude diagnostique de la Direction du Parc National W (DPNW) et problématique de gestion des plantes utilisées dans le traitement de diabète dans les terroirs riverains. Licence Professionnelle, Faculté des Sciences Agronomiques, Université d’Abomey-Calavi, Bénin.						
Johannes Romuald FAGBOHOUN, 2014. Habitats characterization and spatial pattern of Borassus aethiopum (Mart.) in “Trois rivières” Forest Reserve, Benin (West Africa). Diplôme de Master Professionnel, Faculté des Sciences Agronomiques, Université d’Abomey-Calavi, Bénin.						
Josvins Olutogni Fiacre ESSOU, 2015. Analyse diagnostique du secteur forestier de Massi : recensement et importances des espèces de la famille des leguminoseae dans la lama. Licence Professionnelle, Faculté des Sciences Agronomiques, Université d’Abomey-Calavi, Bénin.						
Kafui Inès Edna DELEKE KOKO, 2005. Utilisation des plantes médicinales contre les maladies et troubles gynécologiques dans les terroirs autour de la Zone Cynégétique de la Pendjari (ZCP) du Bénin : compréhension, inventaire ethnobotanique et perspectives pour leur conservation. Diplôme d’Ingénieur Agronome, Faculté des Sciences Agronomiques, Université d’Abomey-Calavi, Bénin.						
Olouwa kemi Massihoundath Laye SANNI, 2011. Jardins de case et conservation de la diversité biologique et bioculturelle dans la zone soudanienne du Benin. Diplôme d’Ingénieur Agronome, Faculté des Sciences Agronomiques, Université d’Abomey-Calavi, Bénin.						
Samson A. DOGNIMON, 2014. Etude diagnostique du cantonnement forestier de Dassa-Zoumè et recensement des plantes médicinales utilisées dans le traitement des maladies mentales. Licence Professionnelle, Faculté des Sciences Agronomiques, Université d’Abomey-Calavi, Bénin.						
Sènan Ingride LEGBA, 2014. Ethnobotanique quantitative de securidaca longepedunculata et impact de son exploitation sur la structure de ses populations naturelles dans la commune de dassa-zoume.  Diplôme de Master Professionnel, Faculté des Sciences Agronomiques, Université d’Abomey-Calavi, Bénin.						
Wassilatou ABDOU IBRAHIMA, 2011. Jardins de case et conservation de la diversité biologique et bioculturelle dans la zone soudano-guinéenne du Bénin. Diplôme d’Ingénieur Agronome, Faculté des Sciences Agronomiques, Université d’Abomey-Calavi, Bénin.						
BEHANZIN Rubinxe, 2016. Identification des paramètres de gestion et de conservation des hippopotames communs (Hippopotamus amphibius) dans la vallée du fleuve Mono. Diplôme d’Ingénieur Agronome, Faculté des Sciences Agronomiques, Université d’Abomey-Calavi, Bénin.						
_ Akoègninou A., Van der Burg W.J., Van der Maesen L.J.G., Flore Analytique du Bénin. Herbier National du Bénin. 1034 pages;  -Hutchinson J., Dalziel J.M., 1954. Flora of West Tropical Africa. Second édition, Vol. I. Part1; 295 pages;  -Hutchinson J., Dalziel J.M., 1958. Flora of West Tropical Africa. Second édition, Vol. I. Part 2; 532 pages;</citation>
              </bibliography>
        </gbif>
    </metadata>
</additionalMetadata>

</eml:eml>
