<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<eml:eml xmlns:eml="eml://ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.1.1" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="eml://ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.1.1 http://rs.gbif.org/schema/eml-gbif-profile/1.1/eml.xsd"
        packageId="9cc68a7f-df2d-49d6-b797-94c99a2cafe8"  system="http://gbif.org" scope="system"
  xml:lang="en">

<dataset>
      <alternateIdentifier>10.15468/wojfbp</alternateIdentifier>
        <alternateIdentifier>http://ipt-benin.gbif.fr/resource?r=tessi_2017</alternateIdentifier>
    <title>List of medicinal and agroforestry plants found in various ecosystems of Benin</title>
    <creator>
    <individualName>
<givenName>Donald Romaric</givenName>          <surName>YEHOUENOU TESSI</surName>
    </individualName>
<organizationName>Laboratory of Forest Sciences, University of Abomey-Calavi</organizationName><positionName>Research Assistant</positionName>    <address>
<city>Calavi</city><administrativeArea>Atlantique</administrativeArea><postalCode>229</postalCode><country>BENIN</country>    </address>
<phone>+22997696308</phone><electronicMailAddress>tdonald3@yahoo.fr</electronicMailAddress>    </creator>
    <metadataProvider>
    <individualName>
<givenName>Donald Romaric</givenName>          <surName>YEHOUENOU TESSI</surName>
    </individualName>
<organizationName>Laboratory of Forest Sciences, University of Abomey-Calavi</organizationName><positionName>Research Assistant</positionName>    <address>
<city>Calavi</city><administrativeArea>Atlantique</administrativeArea><postalCode>229</postalCode><country>BENIN</country>    </address>
<phone>+22997696308</phone><electronicMailAddress>tdonald3@yahoo.fr</electronicMailAddress>    </metadataProvider>
    <associatedParty>
    <individualName>
<givenName>Jean</givenName>          <surName>Ganglo</surName>
    </individualName>
<electronicMailAddress>ganglocj@gmail.com</electronicMailAddress>    <role>USER</role>
    </associatedParty>
      <pubDate>
      2017-06-04
      </pubDate>
    <language>ENGLISH</language>
    <abstract>
        <para>This database includes a list of medicinal and agroforestry species plants collected throughout Benin</para>
    </abstract>
        <keywordSet>
              <keyword>Species diversity</keyword>
              <keyword>Benin</keyword>
              <keyword>medicinal plants</keyword>
              <keyword>Occurrence</keyword>
              <keyword>agroforestry species</keyword>
              <keywordThesaurus>GBIF Dataset Type Vocabulary: http://rs.gbif.org/vocabulary/gbif/dataset_type.xml</keywordThesaurus>
        </keywordSet>
      <intellectualRights>
        <para>This work is licensed under a <ulink url="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/legalcode"><citetitle>Creative Commons Attribution (CC-BY) 4.0 License</citetitle></ulink>.</para>
      </intellectualRights>
      <coverage>
            <geographicCoverage>
                  <geographicDescription>This database includes a list of medicinal and agroforestry species plants collected throughout Benin</geographicDescription>
                  <boundingCoordinates>
                      <westBoundingCoordinate>1.12</westBoundingCoordinate>
                      <eastBoundingCoordinate>3.58</eastBoundingCoordinate>
                      <northBoundingCoordinate>12.4</northBoundingCoordinate>
                      <southBoundingCoordinate>6.33</southBoundingCoordinate>
                  </boundingCoordinates>
            </geographicCoverage>
          <temporalCoverage>
            <rangeOfDates>
              <beginDate>
                <calendarDate>      1996-10-02
</calendarDate>
              </beginDate>
              <endDate>
                <calendarDate>      2017-03-04
</calendarDate>
              </endDate>
            </rangeOfDates>
          </temporalCoverage>
              <taxonomicCoverage>
                    <taxonomicClassification>
                          <taxonRankName>Kingdom</taxonRankName>
                        <taxonRankValue>Plantae</taxonRankValue>
                          <commonName>Plantes</commonName>
                    </taxonomicClassification>
              </taxonomicCoverage>
      </coverage>
      <maintenance>
          <description>
              <para></para>
          </description>
          <maintenanceUpdateFrequency>unkown</maintenanceUpdateFrequency>
      </maintenance>
      <contact>
    <individualName>
<givenName>Donald Romaric</givenName>          <surName>YEHOUENOU TESSI</surName>
    </individualName>
<organizationName>Laboratory of Forest Sciences, University of Abomey-Calavi</organizationName><positionName>Research Assistant</positionName>    <address>
<city>Calavi</city><administrativeArea>Atlantique</administrativeArea><postalCode>229</postalCode><country>BENIN</country>    </address>
<phone>+22997696308</phone><electronicMailAddress>tdonald3@yahoo.fr</electronicMailAddress>      </contact>

      <project id="BID-AF2015-0065-NAC">
          <title>Capacity building and biodiversity data mobilization to address health and food security priorities in Benin</title>
          <personnel>
    <individualName>
<givenName>Jean Cossi</givenName>          <surName>GANGLO</surName>
    </individualName>
    <role>PRINCIPAL_INVESTIGATOR</role>
          </personnel>
          <abstract>
              <para>This project mobilizes data about medicinal plants and multipurpose agroforestry plant species in Benin, strengthening the national network’s capacity and promoting the use of these data in biodiversity conservation.
To achieve this, priority medicinal plants known to treat malaria and important agroforestry species in use in the country are being identified, and workshops on data mobilization and data use are organized. Over 59,000 data records will be published through GBIF.org and the GBIF Benin portal. Relevant data held in collections in France, Netherlands and Belgium are also being gathered and will be published.
The project maps the distribution of targeted species and will suggest conservation strategies to policy makers during workshops on the conservation and sustainable use of</para>
          </abstract>
          <funding>
              <para>The funding of this project is generously provided by European Union in the framework of Biodiversity Information for Development program managed by GBIF Secretariat</para>
          </funding>
            <studyAreaDescription>
                <descriptor name="generic" citableClassificationSystem="false">
                    <descriptorValue>The data digitized and published in the framework of this project are gathered throughout the whole country on the targeted species</descriptorValue>
                </descriptor>
            </studyAreaDescription>
            <designDescription>
                <description>
                    <para>The design is detailed according to the objectives of the project
1) Establish and strengthen national biodiversity information facilities; to achieve this, we will identify priority medicinal plants renowned in healing malaria and priority multipurpose agroforestry plant species used by Beninese. We will organize workshops to capacitate partners to enable them mobilize and use data. We will also digitize, and publish Benin data deposited in France, Netherlands, and Belgium.

2)  Increase available biodiversity data, within and beyond the grant period by providing technical and financial assistance to partner institutions to help them digitize their data. Data mobilized and checklists will be published through GBIF and GBIF Benin portals.

3) Apply biodiversity data in response to national priorities by achieving distribution maps and ecological niche models of the targeted species; we will suggest strategies to conserve and use species and make conclusions on how relevant protected areas are today and in the future with respect to biodiversity conservation and make adequate suggestions to increase their efficiency in protecting biodiversity. Finally, communications and outreach will be elaborated and broadcasted via diverse media to demonstrate to policy and decision makers the value chain: data → knowledge → applications.</para>
                </description>
            </designDescription>
      </project>
</dataset>

<additionalMetadata>
    <metadata>
      <gbif>
        <dateStamp>2020-01-20T15:36:04Z</dateStamp>
      <citation>YEHOUENOU TESSI D R (2017). List of medicinal and agroforestry plants found in various ecosystems of Benin. Laboratory of Forest Sciences (University of Abomey-Calavi). Occurrence dataset https://doi.org/10.15468/wojfbp accessed via GBIF.org on 2020-01-20.</citation>
              <bibliography>
      <citation>_ Akoègninou A., Van der Burg W.J., Van der Maesen L.J.G., Flore Analytique du Bénin. Herbier National du Bénin. 1034 pages;  -Hutchinson J., Dalziel J.M., 1954. Flora of West Tropical Africa. Second édition, Vol. I. Part1; 295 pages;  -Hutchinson J., Dalziel J.M., 1958. Flora of West Tropical Africa. Second édition, Vol. I. Part 2; 532 pages;  						
Goussanou A. Cedric. 2012. Evaluation écologique et ethnobotanique de Sarcocephalus latifolius au Sud Benin. Mémoire de Master en gestion des ressources naturelles et biodiversité. FSA/UAC, 60p.						
HOUDANON RD. 2011. Changements physionomiques et floristiques des terres de parcours de la reserve de biosphere transfrontaliere du W (benin): cas des communes de Banikoara, Kandi et Karimama. These d&apos;Ingenieur, Universite d&apos;Abomey-Calavi. 70 pages; Houinato M., 2001. Phytosociologie, écologie, production et capacité de charge des formations végétales pâturées dans la région des Monts Kouffé (Bénin). Th. Doc. Fac. Se. Lab. Bot. Syst &amp; phyt. Uni. Lib. Bruxelles, Belgique. 219 p.; Natta AK. 1997. Contribution a l&apos;etude de la productivite et de la gestion des paturages naturels dans le Nord-Ouest de l&apos;Atacora: region de Boukoumbe-Materi. These d&apos;Ingenieur, Universite d&apos;Abomey-Calavi. 226 pages; Kassa BD. 1998. Problematique de l&apos;amenagement ecologique pour la conservation des ressources fauniques dans le Parc National du W du Niger: Perimetre de Keremou au Nord-Benin. These d&apos;Ingenieur, Universite d&apos;Abomey-Calavi, Benin. 186 pages						
Lougbegnon TO, Tente B, Amontcha M, Codjia JC. 2011. Importance culturelle et valeur d’usage des ressources végétales de la réserve forestière marécageuse de la vallée de Sitatunga et zones connexes. Bulletin de la Recherche Agronomique du Bénin. Numéro 70; Madjidou Oumorou and Jean Lejoly. 2003. Aperçu de la végétation de quelques inselbergs du Bénin. Systematics and Geography of Plants, Vol. 73, No. 2: 215-236; S. Djègo-Djossou, I. Koné, A. B. Fandohan, J. G. Djègo, M. C. Huynen and B. Sinsin. 2015. Habitat Use by White-Thighed Colobus in the Kikélé Sacred Forest: Activity Budget, Feeding Ecology and Selection of Sleeping Trees. Primate Conservation, (29):97-105.						
CeRGeT-ONG. 2011. Rapport final de la réalisation de l’étude de référence sur la diversité biologique des massifs forestiers des trois rivières, de Sota, de Goungoun, de Dogo-Ketou, de l’Ouémé supérieur - N’dali. Programme de Gestion des Forêts et Terroirs Riverains. HUNYET Ousmane. 2013. Rapport de l’étude d’inventaire de la biodiversité des forêts sacrées des sites RAMSAR 1017 et 1018 du Bénin. Avant-projet PP 165/12rev.1(f) « étude pour la restauration et la gestion des forets sacrées des sites RAMSAR 1017 et 1018 du Bénin ». Brice Sinsin, Julien Djègo, Houngbo Emile, Rémy Houéhounha, Toussaint Lougbégnon, Vincent Orékan, Quinette Tchintchin. 2010. Rapport final de l’étude de la diversité biologique dans les périmètres de reboisement de Kilir et d’Abomey appartenant à l’aire d’intervention du PGFTR au Benin. MEHU / DGFRN / PIFSAP. 2013. Base de donnees sur la biodiversité des forets sacrées. Version 1.0.0. www.dgfrn-bj.org/pifsap/accueil.php. Achigan‐Dako, E.G., Pasquini M.W., Assogba‐Komlan F., N’danikou S., Yédomonhan H., Dansi A., Ambrose‐Oji B. 2010. Traditional vegetables in Benin. Institut National des Recherches Agricoles du Bénin. Imprimeries du CENAP, Cotonou. Sinadouwirou Th, Sokpon N, Gbaguidi f, Biaou SH. 2001. Aperçu sur les forêts édaphiques hygrophiles du Bénin. Belgian Journal of Botany, Vol. 134, Fasc. 1, pp. 79-93. 						
Hèdégbètan GC (2011) Etude écologique de l’îlot forestier Bahazoun dans la Vallée du Sitatunga, arrondissement de Kpanroun (Commune d’Abomey-Calavi), Bénin. Licence Professionnelle (Université Abomey-Calavi.)</citation>
              </bibliography>
        </gbif>
    </metadata>
</additionalMetadata>

</eml:eml>
