<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<eml:eml xmlns:eml="eml://ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.1.1" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="eml://ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.1.1 http://rs.gbif.org/schema/eml-gbif-profile/1.1/eml.xsd"
        packageId="a19f9ba6-4869-4124-b3ef-8b885e16a4d2"  system="http://gbif.org" scope="system"
  xml:lang="en">

<dataset>
      <alternateIdentifier>10.15468/m0cqdu</alternateIdentifier>
        <alternateIdentifier>http://ipt.gbifbenin.org/resource?r=toko_02</alternateIdentifier>
        <alternateIdentifier>a19f9ba6-4869-4124-b3ef-8b885e16a4d2</alternateIdentifier>
        <alternateIdentifier>http://ipt-benin.gbif.fr/resource?r=toko_02</alternateIdentifier>
    <title>Diversité floristique des espèces menacées prioritaires du Bénin (Afrique de l&apos;Ouest).</title>
    <creator>
    <individualName>
<givenName>Ismaïla</givenName>          <surName>TOKO IMOROU</surName>
    </individualName>
<organizationName>Laboratoire de Cartographie</organizationName><positionName>Professor</positionName>    <address>
<administrativeArea>Atlantique</administrativeArea><postalCode>229</postalCode><country>BENIN</country>    </address>
<phone>+22997772872</phone><electronicMailAddress>ismael_toko@yahoo.fr</electronicMailAddress>    </creator>
    <metadataProvider>
    <individualName>
<givenName>Erick</givenName>          <surName>SOGBOSSI</surName>
    </individualName>
<organizationName>Laboratoire de Cartographie</organizationName><positionName>Research Assistant</positionName>    <address>
<administrativeArea>Atlantique</administrativeArea><postalCode>229</postalCode><country>BENIN</country>    </address>
<phone>+22996114887</phone><electronicMailAddress>ericksogbossi@gmail.com</electronicMailAddress>    </metadataProvider>
    <metadataProvider>
    <individualName>
<givenName>Sakibou</givenName>          <surName>BIAOU</surName>
    </individualName>
<organizationName>Laboratoire de Cartographie</organizationName><positionName>Researcher</positionName>    <address>
<administrativeArea>Atlantique</administrativeArea><postalCode>229</postalCode><country>BENIN</country>    </address>
    </metadataProvider>
    <metadataProvider>
    <individualName>
<givenName>Aïssétou</givenName>          <surName>GOBI MOHAMED</surName>
    </individualName>
<organizationName>Laboratoire de Cartographie</organizationName><positionName>Research assistant</positionName>    <address>
<administrativeArea>Atlantique</administrativeArea><postalCode>229</postalCode><country>BENIN</country>    </address>
    </metadataProvider>
    <associatedParty>
    <individualName>
<givenName>Jean</givenName>          <surName>Ganglo</surName>
    </individualName>
<electronicMailAddress>ganglocj@gmail.com</electronicMailAddress>    <role>USER</role>
    </associatedParty>
      <pubDate>
      2018-11-24
      </pubDate>
    <language>ENGLISH</language>
    <abstract>
        <para>Les occurrences des espèces ont été obtenues à partir des données de relevés phytosociologiques et d&amp;#39;inventaires forestiers issues des travaux de recherche de Licence, de Maîtrise et de Thèse de Doctorat dans les Universités d&amp;#39;Abomey-Calavi et de Parakou.</para>
    </abstract>
        <keywordSet>
              <keyword>Bélléfoungou</keyword>
              <keyword>Dunkassa</keyword>
              <keyword>Koudo</keyword>
              <keyword>Kalalé</keyword>
              <keyword>Nagayilé</keyword>
              <keyword>Aklampa</keyword>
              <keyword>Bassila</keyword>
              <keyword>Sakabansi</keyword>
              <keyword>Gobada</keyword>
              <keyword>Wari-Maro</keyword>
              <keyword>Banguirétamou</keyword>
              <keyword>Sempéto</keyword>
              <keyword>Occurrence</keyword>
              <keywordThesaurus>GBIF Dataset Type Vocabulary: http://rs.gbif.org/vocabulary/gbif/dataset_type.xml</keywordThesaurus>
        </keywordSet>
      <intellectualRights>
        <para>This work is licensed under a <ulink url="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/legalcode"><citetitle>Creative Commons Attribution (CC-BY) 4.0 License</citetitle></ulink>.</para>
      </intellectualRights>
      <coverage>
            <geographicCoverage>
                  <geographicDescription>Les occurrences des espèces ont été obtenues à partir des données de relevés phytosociologiques et d&apos;inventaires forestiers issues des travaux de recherche de Licence, de Maîtrise et de Thèse de Doctorat dans les Universités d&apos;Abomey-Calavi et de Parakou.</geographicDescription>
                  <boundingCoordinates>
                      <westBoundingCoordinate>0.933</westBoundingCoordinate>
                      <eastBoundingCoordinate>3.742</eastBoundingCoordinate>
                      <northBoundingCoordinate>12.341</northBoundingCoordinate>
                      <southBoundingCoordinate>6.327</southBoundingCoordinate>
                  </boundingCoordinates>
            </geographicCoverage>
          <temporalCoverage>
            <rangeOfDates>
              <beginDate>
                <calendarDate>      2005-04-29
</calendarDate>
              </beginDate>
              <endDate>
                <calendarDate>      2017-12-15
</calendarDate>
              </endDate>
            </rangeOfDates>
          </temporalCoverage>
              <taxonomicCoverage>
                    <taxonomicClassification>
                          <taxonRankName>Kingdom</taxonRankName>
                        <taxonRankValue>Plantae</taxonRankValue>
                          <commonName>Plantes</commonName>
                    </taxonomicClassification>
              </taxonomicCoverage>
      </coverage>
      <maintenance>
          <description>
              <para></para>
          </description>
          <maintenanceUpdateFrequency>unkown</maintenanceUpdateFrequency>
      </maintenance>
      <contact>
    <individualName>
<givenName>Ismaïla</givenName>          <surName>TOKO IMOROU</surName>
    </individualName>
<organizationName>Laboratoire de Cartographie</organizationName><positionName>Professor</positionName>    <address>
<administrativeArea>Atlantique</administrativeArea><postalCode>229</postalCode><country>BENIN</country>    </address>
<phone>+22997772872</phone><electronicMailAddress>ismael_toko@yahoo.fr</electronicMailAddress>      </contact>
      <methods>
            <methodStep>
                <description>
                    <para>Exploration of vegetation and sampling plots of 18m of radius in plant communities and species census with the plots</para>
                </description>
            </methodStep>
            <sampling>
                <studyExtent>
                    <description>
                        <para>Whole Benin</para>
                    </description>
                </studyExtent>
                <samplingDescription>
                    <para>Installation de placeaux (circulaire de 18 m de rayon) de releves phytosociologiques suivant la methode sigmatiste de Braun-Blanquet (1932)</para>
                </samplingDescription>
            </sampling>
      </methods>

      <project id="BID-AF2015-0066-REG">
          <title>Capacity building and biodiversity data mobilization for conservation, sustainable use, and decision making in Africa and Madagascar</title>
          <personnel>
    <individualName>
<givenName>Jean Cossi</givenName>          <surName>GANGLO</surName>
    </individualName>
    <role>PRINCIPAL_INVESTIGATOR</role>
          </personnel>
          <abstract>
              <para>This project to mobilize biodiversity data and identify conservation priorities will be implemented by a consortium of eight African countries – Senegal, Côte-d’Ivoire, Mali, Guinea, DRC, Niger, Madagascar, and Benin.
Training workshops organized by the University of Kansas will help build the data publishing capacity of project partners. The consortium will identify priority invasive alien species and threatened species for data mobilization, and publish relevant data from collections in France, Netherlands and Belgium. More than 200,000 records of biodiversity data will be made available through GBIF.org and national portals.
Based on published data, the consortium will develop distribution maps of priority species, suggest actions to monitor and control the spread of invasive alien species and provide recommendations for the conservation of threatened species.</para>
          </abstract>
          <funding>
              <para>The funding of this project is generously provided by European Union in the framework of Biodiversity Information for Development program managed by GBIF Secretariat</para>
          </funding>
            <studyAreaDescription>
                <descriptor name="generic" citableClassificationSystem="false">
                    <descriptorValue>The data digitized and published in the framework of this project are gathered throughout the country members on the targeted species</descriptorValue>
                </descriptor>
            </studyAreaDescription>
            <designDescription>
                <description>
                    <para>Despite its utmost importance to the survival of humanity, biodiversity is subject to many threats. As a significant step toward overcoming these threats, we submit this project in the framework of a consortium of eight African countries - Senegal, Côte-d’Ivoire, Mali, Guinea, DRC, Niger, Madagascar, and Benin - to achieve the following goals: 
1) Establish and strengthen international collaborations to mobilize biodiversity data; to achieve that goal, we will identify priority invasive alien species and threatened species to be considered in the consortium. We will organize workshops at regional level under the umbrella of the University of Kansas (USA), our Non-ACP partner, to capacitate project partners. We will digitize and publish data of consortium countries deposited in France, Netherlands, and Belgium. 
2) Increase available biodiversity data, within and beyond the grant period, by capacitating and providing financial assistance to in-country partners to encourage them mobilize and publish their data through GBIF and national portals. 
3) Apply biodiversity data in response to conservation priorities by achieving the following: elaborate distribution maps of threatened species and invasive alien species; identify the main threats to species and suggest efficient actions to protect and conserve them; identify and suggest efficient actions to monitor and eradicate invasive alien species; evaluate the efficiency of protected areas with respect to biodiversity conservation and make adequate suggestions; finally, from our results, elaborate and broadcast communication and outreach via diverse media so as to demonstrate to policy- and decision-makers the value chain: data → knowledge → applications.</para>
                </description>
            </designDescription>
      </project>
</dataset>

<additionalMetadata>
    <metadata>
      <gbif>
        <dateStamp>2020-01-20T15:36:10Z</dateStamp>
      <citation>TOKO IMOROU I, SOGBOSSI E, BIAOU S, GOBI MOHAMED A (2018). Diversité floristique des espèces menacées prioritaires du Bénin (Afrique de l&apos;Ouest).. Version 1.1. Laboratory of Forest Sciences (University of Abomey-Calavi). Occurrence dataset https://doi.org/10.15468/m0cqdu accessed via GBIF.org on 2020-01-20.</citation>
              <bibliography>
      <citation>Ali M. F. K. R., 2015. Déterminants écologiques, anthropologiques et socio-économiques pour la conservation et la gestion durable des forêts sacrées et communautaires de la Basse vallée de l’Ouémé dans le bénin méridional. Thèse de Doctorat, DGAT/FLASH, Université d’Abomey-Calavi, 210 p + annexes.						
Boukari S., 2015. Effet de la taille et de l’isolement sur la diversité floristique des reliques forestières de la Lagune Côtière du Bénin. DEA/DGAT/FASHS/UAC, Bénin, 111 p.						
Zankpe G. R., 2015. Diversité floristique et stratégies endogènes de gestion des forêts sacrées dans la Commune de Savalou. Mémoire de maîtrise en géographie, DGAT/FASHS/UAC, 147 p.						
Biao F. C., 2014. Impacts écologiques et socio-économiques de l&apos;écorçage des plantes medicinales dans les forêts de la Lama et de Lokoli. Mémoire de maîtrise en géographie, DGAT/FASHS/UAC, 112 p.						
Bete S. S., Toko I. I., 2011. Evaluation de la contribution des forêts sacrées à la conservation de la biodiversité végétale du Sud-Bénin. Rapport d’étude, Projet d’Appui à la Gestion des Forêts Communales, 54 p + annexes.						
Sogbossi S. E., 2010. Dynamique de reconstitution des formations végétales sèches de terre ferme dans le nord Bénin : Cas des forêts sacrées de l’axe Parakou – Natitingou. Mémoire d’Ingénieur Agronome, FA/UP, Parakou, Bénin, 190 p + annexes.						
Toko I. I., 2008. Etude de la variabilité spatiale de la biomasse herbacée, de la phénologie et de la structure de la végétation le long des topos séquences du bassin supérieur du fleuve Ouémé au Bénin. Thèse de Doctorat, FLASH/UAC, 241 p.</citation>
              </bibliography>
        </gbif>
    </metadata>
</additionalMetadata>

</eml:eml>
